one of the kitchen today because I'm
working from harm so you know sometimes
I just have to be here hey what's up
guys my name is Anna welcome back to my
staples last series today we're gonna be
talking about Elle values and our values
so is it just a zoom lens I don't
usually shoot one a zoom lens Pam today
so I had to I had to do that this is
gonna be the first video in a series of
videos which essentially is gonna be
talking about some more advanced staples
plus features including move semantics I
don't know if this will just cover move
semantics because there's obviously a
lot more that this information will help
you with and just learning about
basically move semantics but it is
definitely a huge prerequisite for that
if you don't know what an l-value is if
you don't know what an r-value is
especially then it's gonna be a little
bit difficult for you to kind of
understand how the more advanced c++
features such as move semantics look
this is definitely one of those things
that is very difficult to just explain
by waving my hands like I tend to do for
most of my video we're definitely gonna
jump into some code I'm gonna show you
guys how this stuff works and what it is
and more importantly why you care but
first I want to thank Skillshare for
sponsoring this video if you guys have
not heard of Skillshare yet then you
clearly haven't been watching most of my
videos Skillshare is an online learning
community where millions of creatives
and curious people all around the world
come together to deepen an existing
passion or hobby or learn something new
and unlike other kind of online
communities Skillshare is specifically
curated to teach you something new and
with videos that are like super short
super easy to understand super OnPoint
it's a really efficient place for you to
learn something new I know that a lot of
people are anxious with what's going on
in the world right now I know that I
definitely am and I think being creative
and learning something is a really good
way to kind of put your mind out of that
and also deepen something that you might
have always wanted to do you'll share
have so many amazing classes that will
teach you just so many things
photography videography how to start a
YouTube channel and market that and
start a successful business I mean
seriously they've even got classes on
how you can like rearrange the furniture
in your room to make it better
as I mentioned before I particularly
love their illustration classes because
I think that artwork is something that's
really hard to teach well and I guess I
just really enjoyed the way that
Skillshare manages to communicate all of
those ideas across and a lesson $10 a
month for an annual subscription I think
that is a really useful asset to have in
your library of learning and information
and skill sure have been nice enough to
offer the first 1,000 people who sign up
using my link in the description below
two months of free Skillshare premium so
especially if you're sitting at home now
in this period two months for free try
it out and see what new stuff you could
learn huge thank you again to Skillshare
for sponsoring not just me but other
fellow youtubers in this difficult time
I have to say I really like working with
companies who are actually nice and
Skillshare is definitely one of them
Before we jump into some card and take a
look at what L values and our values
actually I just kind of want to explain
to you roughly what they are and why
it's important for you to kind of
recognize what they are and we're not
just going to be talking about L values
and our values in this video we're going
to also be touching l value references
and our value of references these are
kind of words I guess that a lot of
samples loss program is here but they
don't quite understand and especially if
you're unusual language you might just
get compiler error as saying words like
L value R value must be an L value must
be a modifiable R value known constant
value and you might be like okay why is
why is the compiler giving me such
cryptic language why can't this language
be more straightforward language being
simple plus why can't it be more
straightforward why do they have to have
all these fancy words and the words are
only fancy if you turn on what they mean
if you know what the words mean they
kind of lose their fanciness and they
actually make sense and this video is
hopefully gonna clear a lot of that up
for you guys
now a lot of people call L values
locator values because they have some
kind of location as we'll see in a
minute but there are many different ways
to kind of define L values and our
values and I don't think that you should
stick to like trying to basically you
know find a definition for the letter L
of letter R you just need to know what
an L value isn't an R value is don't try
and kind of define it for yourself
because I feel like that's a little
a bit of a trap okay so let's start with
a super simple definition of what an L
value is and what an R value is suppose
I have a variable let's just call it I
will set it to ten we have two parts to
this expression we have a left side and
a right side and this is also another
good way to think about what an L value
is in what an R value is an L value is a
lot of the times something that is on
the left side of the equal sign and then
an R value is something that is on the
right side of the equal sign now this
does not always apply so I'm not gonna
like say this is just a complete fact to
always think of it that way because it's
not necessarily true but in this case it
is we have a variable called I which is
of course an actual variable with a
location in memory and then we have
simply a value just a numeric literal
it's just ten it has no storage it has
no location until it is assigned to an L
value which is what I is this makes
sense because you can't assign something
to an R value so otherwise I can't say
10 equals I or something like that that
would be weird because 10 is not
something that has a location we can't
store data in ten however this is an L
value now obviously we could just make
another variable called a and set it
equal to I in this case we're setting an
L value equal to something it is also an
L value which is why I was saying that
whole like right side of the equal sign
doesn't always make sense and our value
doesn't just have to be a literal like
this it can also be the result of a
function maybe we have a function called
get value which returns 10 and then we
call this function here now in this case
get value returns an R value it returns
a temporary value it's temporary because
even though it does return an int it has
no location it has no storage
it's just returning the value 10 but
what we're doing here is taking that R
value that temporary value and storing
it into an L value now because this is
an R value if we try and assign
something to that R value it's not gonna
work this expression is not gonna work
why because this is an R value and you
can see that our compiler is helping us
as saying that expression must be a
modifiable L value modifiable meaning it
has to be non Const an L value meaning
it has to be an L value however this is
where it gets interesting
if this was to return an L value which
we could do by returning
int reference this is called an l-value
reference and I would need to obviously
provide some kind of storage for my
value maybe by using a static int like
this and then returning it if this is
the case since this is now an L value is
pretending an L value reference I can
assign to it and this expression works
fine so that's what an L value reference
is to expand on this a little bit if I
had a function that took in a value
maybe we'll call it set value I can call
this function a number of ways I can
call it with an L value or an R value
I'll set I back to ten and then I'll
call set value with that variable so
here I'm calling set value with an L
value and then here I'm calling set
value with an R value so this is a
temporary value and R value I keep
repeating myself just so you guys really
get the point here so in this case what
will happen is this hour value will be
used to create an L value when the
function is actually called now we can
instantly see which one of these is
temporary and which is not because
another rule is that you cannot take an
L value reference from an R value so you
can only have an L value reference of an
L value and we can easily check this if
I stick an ampersand over here so now
I'm taking an interest is an L value
reference you can see that this
immediately gives me an error it says
that the initial value of reference to
non Const be an L value now you've
probably noticed so far there's a lot of
mention of like Const non constant
what's the deal here well there's
actually a special rule and that is that
whilst I can't have an L value reference
of an R value so in other words I can't
have something like this if it's a Const
L value reference I can so if you're
right Const here you can see this works
this is just a special rule it's kind of
a little bit of a workaround
realistically what happens is that the
compiler will probably create like a
temporary variable with your actual
storage and then assign it to that
reference like that so really it's just
they're not to kind of avoid creating an
L value but rather to just kind of
support both our values and L values
because what I can do here is make this
an our const reference and you can see
that it accepts both types of data it
accepts an l value and an R value
because a Const l value reference can in
fact
cept both of them okay let's scratch
this example and take a look at another
one this time using strings I'll have a
first name which I'll set to my first
name and then I'll have a last name
which I will set to my last name then
what I'll do is I'll create a third
string which is gonna be my full name
and I'll set this equal to first name
plus last name ignoring the space that
I'm not adding between the two strings
so take a good look at this and try and
identify what you think an l-value is
and what the our values are so in this
case everything on the left side here is
an L value and everything on the right
side here isn't our value so in other
words this is an R value this is an L
value this expression here is an R value
it's a temporary object what happens is
a temporary string gets constructed from
these two and then it gets assigned into
an L value so with that same kind of
rule in mind if I had a function called
print name which took in an S City
string name here and then let's just say
we print it here then if I try and call
this function print name with full name
it's gonna work fine but if I try and
call it with this expression that we had
here that's not going to work because
it's an R value which is why you'll see
a lot of conferences being written in
C++ because as you can see they're
compatible with both temporaries R
values and also actual kind of real
existing variables L values so we
clearly have a way to detect whether or
not something is an actual L value we
can do that by just writing an L value
reference that's non Const an L value
reference can only accept L values this
will not compile because this of course
is an R value do we have a way to write
a function that only accepts temporary
objects yes and for that we need to use
something called an r-value reference
and our value reference looks the same
as an L value reference except we use
two ampersands instead of one so you can
see what's happened here is the errors
of switch now we can't pass in an L
value but we can pass in an R value and
if we hover our mouse over here and look
at the error message it says an R value
reference cannot be bound to an L value
so that makes sense this is pretty cool
because it means that we can actually
write an overload of this function that
accepts only temporary
Jax and one that accepts L values and
even if we make this Const meaning that
it's also going to be compatible with
our values this overload will still be
chosen if it exists so if we take a look
at our code here I might just write L
value and then I'll do the same thing
over here except I'll write our value if
we now call all of these and I'll just
do a little STD seems I guess that the
console doesn't close you can see that
the first overload that was chosen was
the L value 1 and then the second one
was the R value 1 so this is all really
cool because with our value references
we now have a way to actually detect
temporary values and do something
special to them so the question now
might be well ok but how is this useful
and the answer is well it's very useful
especially with move semantics but
that's going to be a topic for another
video basically the main advantage here
is to do with optimization if we know
that we're taking in a temporary object
then we don't have to worry about making
sure that we keep it alive and making
sure we keep it intact making sure we
copy it we can simply steal the
resources that might be attached to that
specific object and use them somewhere
else because we know that it's temporary
it's not going to exist for very long
whereas if you take in something like
this then you can't I mean apart from
the fact that it's cost you can't really
steal anything from this name string
because it might be used in a number of
functions whereas this is clearly
something that is temporary only going
to be used with this particular call of
print name and that's where the power
really comes from so remember L values
are basically variables that have some
kind of storage back in them our values
are temporary values l value references
can only take in l values unless they're
Const and our value references only take
in these temporary R values you know I
have this video Syrus playing with the
paprika for this video makes sense
for you guys as I say I'm definitely one
of those topics that a lot of people are
very confused about so hopefully this
video helped to kind of clear the air a
little bit as to what l values and our
values are as I kind of progress with
this series and specifically this kind
of sum of semantics situation it will
definitely become a lot more clear as to
why it's important to know if you're
dealing with an R value reference and if
you can in fact steal the resources
from that temporary value because it is
temporary it really does help a lot with
optimization and it's also very useful
it's very important information to know
in general if you want to know how sales
class actually works and when you're
kind of killing with the code like that
because again a lot of the time you
might be looking through some code you
might see that double ampersand that R
value reference and you might be like I
have no idea what this means or why I
care but hopefully with this you now nor
never have you guys enjoyed this video
if you did please hit that like button
also don't forget to check out
Skillshare first thousand people who use
my link in description blur get free
access to two months of skill shaped
premium go and learn something new I
will see you next time goodbye
[Music]